Lachlan Franckx

Los Angeles, CA (408) 499-2830 Ifranckx@gmail.com

Junior Front-End Developer

Portfolio GitHub LinkedIn

I am a full-stack web developer specializing in React, Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL. My experience as a programmer has taught me how to collaborate in a team, be resourceful, self-reflecting, and patient. I am continuing my growth in software development by learning new technologies and mobile development technologies like React Native.

Skills

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks & Libraries: React, ¡Query, Express

Technologies: Node.js, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs, AJAX, AWS-S3, Multer, Enzyme

Developer Tools: Chrome Dev Tools, Git/GitHub

Projects

Travelog | GitHub:

- Travel blogging sites for travel enthusiasts to connect and share stories and communicate on a unique platform.
- Focused on creating great product usability and building an elegant UI to enhance the user experience.
- Built an Express server that uses Multer middleware to communicate with an AWS S3 bucket for file storage and integrates with a relational database using PostgreSQL and Knex.

Rate My Baby | GitHub:

- This is a humorous app designed for parents who enjoy posting pictures of their babies to social media. Parents can upload photos and create profiles of their babies for the rest of the world to rate.
- Created a user authenticated system utilizing JSON Web Token and bcrypt for hashing passwords.
- Built an Express server to store all user data and incorporated an AWS S3 bucket for file storage to integrate with a RESTful API.

Education

Thinkful/Bloc Remote

Web Development Career Training

July 2019 - May 2020

- Full-stack coding course focused on the iterative development cycle using new technologies and industry best practices.
- Built Express servers and relational databases using PostgreSQL and Knex which support all CRUD operations.
- Managed complex projects using agile development and maintaining version control using Git and Github.

Experience

Majordomo Los Angeles, CA

Server

Sept. 2019 - March 2020

- Enhanced guest dining experience by paying attention to details, consolidating steps, and bringing enthusiasm and knowledge to the menu.
- Developed an excellent teamwork ethic by consistently being punctual, reliable, and leading by example.
- Promoted to a server by taking the initiative to constantly learn and improve my knowledge and capabilities.

Self-Employed Los Angeles, CA

Musician Jan. 2009 - Current

• Recorded and toured professionally across the country and internationally teaching me skills in independence, collaboration, time-management, flexibility, boldness, self-sufficiency, improvisation, and self-marketing.